- Oh my goodness!
我的天啊！
Are we actually going thrifting again? Yes!
我们又要去淘二手了吗？没错！
In fact, I've never stopped.
实际上，我一直在淘
It's just, it's been cut down dramatically over the past year or so
只不过，去年以来由于一堆事情，出门次数少了许多
due to ongoing circumstances as they are.
But yeah, even when I have gone, not very frequently,
当然，我还是能出去的
but whenever I go, it's just not the same, you know,
但是没有之前那样的感觉了
there's not really the same amount or quality of
没有那么多有意思的东西给大家在节目中看了
just interesting things to show
on any kind of episode of "Thrifts."
So, I just haven't acquired as much footage
所以，我就没有很快地积累很多的素材
as quickly and yeah,
that's why it's taken however many months it has
进而我花了好几个月来积累出一集“淘二手”
to get another real thrifting episode out.
But, here we are.
不过，视频终于出来了
I have accumulated enough footage
我积累了很多素材，剪在一起给大家看
and put it all together for your viewing pleasure.
So, let's go thrifting!
那么，咱们淘二手去！
淘二手系列
LGR
第46期 终于线下了
Oh yeah. It's a nice day out.
啊，今天天儿不错
And it's nice to be back at Goodwill again.
能回到GoodWill也是很好的
And as soon as I got inside,
我一进门呢，我看到了一些之前没见过的东西
I'm greeted by a slightly different sight than usual,
a bunch of electronics near the front of the store
店面把很多电器放在了店门口，而不是后面
instead of the back.
Including a whole bunch of neat little monitors
包括很多耐人的小显示器
but, what drew my eye even more
不过，更吸引我眼球的
was this 1950s' looking Magnavox stereo system
是这个上世纪50年代的Magnavox立体音响
with a turntable, made in England apparently.
还有一个唱片机，很明显是英国产的
Check out that old logo, that old design just everything about this.
看看这个老商标，老设计，仔细看看就好了嘛
SuperBart：貌似咱上世纪的电器都是那种绿色，木纹色啥的吧
That paint job with the tan and black
棕黑配色，还有香槟金，真就那味呗
and kind of champagne gold. Oh yeah.
And up above that with all those monitors,
而这上面的嘛，就是些显示器了
there were a bunch of 4:3 aspect ratio ones that caught my attention.
我注意到有很多4:3的显示器
But, the main one that did was this NEC Multi Sync 1540 M.
不过，更吸引我的是这个 NEC Multi Sync 1540 M
Nice little 15 inch deals.
挺耐人的15吋显示器
Got built in speakers,
还有内置扬声器
missing some components around back,
后面看上去少了点东西
which was kind of unfortunate, but you know,
有点可惜，不过你要是喜欢4:3比例的话，这显示器挺好的
nice monitor for someone in need of that aspect ratio.
And hey, just around the corner from that was
转过这个角，我看到一大堆唱片
no shortage of old records,
including a whole box full of
上面是一大堆33转的
SuperBart：要是里面有一张Genesis的话......
33 1/3 vinyl on top.
And a whole bunch of 12 inch
下面的就是一些10吋，12吋的唱片了
and 10 inch records down below that.
That are much more substantial,
这还有一大堆虫胶唱片，一大堆RCA胜利啥的
shellac type of things. Yeah.
Whole lot of RCA Victor stuff.
An intriguing collection, although mostly covered in mold and you could smell it.
挺有意思的收藏，尽管多数发霉，大老远都能闻得到:-P
SuperBart：你要不发霉的话，价格也便宜不了
Just out from there in the media,
进到音像区，我看到了两个有意思的东西
a couple of things caught my eye immediately.
Namely, Microsoft Encarta: 1994 Edition on CD-ROM.
首先是CD版微软百科全书，1994版
SuperBart：感谢这年头有互联网吧，那时我老师要查资料，得老去图书馆
听歌的话就广播录进磁带，或是买实体，还不一定有
It's a little bit older than I normally see in terms of Encarta releases.
而这个版本的软件，比我见到的要老一点
And Hey, this is an AST OEM version.
而且呢，还是个AST OEM版
So, packed in with one of their Advantage computers probably.
显然是和他们卖的电脑绑定的呗
Oh, and of course we got a Zoombinis game down there too.
哇，这下面还有一个Zoombinis游戏
"Zoombinis Island Odyssey."
"Zoombinis 小岛大冒险"
Mm! Nothing I'm needing and neither was this.
好吧，都不太需要，这两个也是
But it was just darn pleasant to see
不过能看到一些大盒装游戏挺好的，越大越好啊
we've got a couple of big box games or bigger boxes.
With the first one, a CD-ROM classics edition of "Wing Commander Privateer."
第一个呢，Wing Commander Privateer CD经典版
And their slimmer very cost reduced box.
盒子很薄，一看就很廉价
And below that, the ever-present "Myst."
接下来的呢，是这个经常看到的Myst
Pretty much guarantee you'll see one of these
基本上去一家GoodWill都会看到的
at every single Goodwill period.
But, you don't always see it in the box.
但是，你很少能看到盒装的
So you know what, whatever, I haven't been to thrift stores in a long time.
也许我老久没来淘二手，一切都不一样了吧
So this was kind of exciting just to see a big box PC game in a while again.
能在呆家里那么长时间后，看到盒装电子游戏，有点小兴奋呢
And even more exciting than that,
更兴奋的是，还能顺路看到盒装软件
seeing a boxed application in the wild.
Oh!
:-)
Now this is increasingly my thing as the years go on.
淘二手多了，这玩意现在很能吸引我
I don't know what's wrong with me, but whatever man.
我也不知道我怎么了，不过无所谓了
"PrintMaster Gold" for Windows,
Windows 版 PrintMaster Gold
in the box with the stuff and the disks.
盒装的，有配件和软盘
Yes, please.
真是很让人很高兴呢
I did not have a version of "PrintMaster" this old
我没有这么老版本的PrintMaster
and I'm rather fond of these print programs. I don't know.
我也很喜欢这些软件，怎么说呢
I just like 'em all.
就是很喜欢了
So this one I'm grabbing and putting it on my shelf.
我要买一份，放在书架上
Mm. Got milk? Or, at least a bunch of milk,
喝牛奶了吗? 或者说，搞到一堆牛奶
Jerry Smith: Hungry for Apple?
what are these?
这都是些啥？
Jugs? Cans?
牛奶壶还是牛奶罐？
Whatever you call them. Those classic almost antique cans.
不管咋叫了，看看这上古时期的牛奶罐
Looking like they've been out in the elements for a while.
看上去老久都没用过了
SuperBart: 我家里还有需要上弦的钟，现在还在用，上世纪80年代生产的吧。
But hey, if that's aluminum, I'm sure that's uh... a material.
不过呢，这要是铝壶的话，也算是个合适的东西吧
And then over by a shelf near the front of the store
店面前面的货架大半，是一大堆旧书籍
was an intriguing selection of older books.
Mostly from the early 20th century,
大多数20世纪早期的，少数19世纪
some late 19th century.
But all marked $5,
全部标价5美元
注：2021年8月1日行情 1USD = 6.46RMB
which is way more than books normally go for at Goodwill.
比平常去GoodWill看到的书还要多
I guess cause they thought they were old
也许是因为他们很老，就给放在了一起
they could mark 'em up but,
there's like an antique shop just down the road
就像同一条路上的一家古董店，卖很多的老书
SuperBart：天津以前有个鬼市，我在那里花了4块钱买了一本90年代的《三国演义》
that sells like a whole group of old books,
this old or older, for five bucks for like 10 of them.
那家店的更老，好像每10本5美元的
So, yeah these've been there for like six months now.
不过，这些书摆在这里好像6个月了
Ooh, hey yeah.
Woo～
Check out this Rolodex.
看看这个名片收集盒
All metal except for the parts that aren't,
大多数是金属的，除了某些部分看上去是胶木做的
which kind of felt like Bakelite, but yeah,
classic Rolodex logo and clunky sound of moving this thing around,
经典的Rolodex商标，转动时候的咔哒声
1960s kind of thing.
真就60年代那种感觉呗
Just a little older than most I come across.
比我平常看到的样子要老一些
And then up above the balls,
上面一堆球(不要想歪了)
we got a little guy here.
还有这个小玩意
Who is this?
这是个啥？
A spark plug with a party hat?
带着派对帽子的火花塞？
Ah, he's skiing.
好吧，还在滑雪呢
Sparky Do-or-Die.
“微笑着面对躺平”
Oh, okay.
:-P
Sparky you do you.
那就微笑吧
Can tell he's got a real spring in his step.
不知道可不可以上弦
Oh hey look at this.
来看看这个
We've got some lighter hued woodgrain down here,
貌似是某种木纹色调的玩意
turntable from Zenith.
Zenith牌唱机
Yeah. Just a lot of mid-century goodies
八成有很多上世纪中期的东西最近在Goodwill上架了
have been running across lately at these Goodwills.
Look at this cool turntable.
看看这转盘，旋钮和其他组件
Those knobs and all the components
painted white in the middle there.
中间上了白色
I don't know.
兴许是吧
Just gotta design that really appeals.
这设计令人舒适
Ooh. Also appealing in a different way
这还有个吸引人的JVC卡座
Is this JVC down here,
a KD-A55 stereo cassette deck.
KD-A55 双声道立体声卡座
Fantastic looking VU meters.
VU表挺耐人的
The red has faded into a yellowish-gold
右边的红色还能渐变为金色的呢
but, I have always dug this JVC aesthetic.
我就喜欢JVC这设计
And the fact that the tape deck is on the right
还有一件事，放磁带的地方在右边，而不是左边
instead of the left is yeah.
It's, it's kind of a thing I enjoy.
挺有意思的细节呢
Has a nice metal tape inside too, which that's pretty cool on its own.
里面还有一盘四类金属带，磁带本身就很有料了
You don't see those terribly often in the wild. Yeah.
平常不太常见，总体而言
Overall an impressive little deck.
这卡座让人很印象深刻
And just down from that, I was intrigued by this little carrying case
而这下面的呢，我被这个小盒子吸引了
thought it might be binoculars or something, but, nope.
觉得里面会是望远镜啥的，可并不是
Check this out.
揭晓答案：就是个装喇叭的盒子，Radio Shack销售的
It's just a little thing made for holding Realistic speakers from Radio Shack.
Heh! From their Minimus line of speakers.
行吧，就是Minimus系列的扬声器
I don't know. I just like the case that they came in. And that was that.
怎么说呢，挺喜欢这个盒子的，就这样
I see Okidata. Yeah. Classic dot matrix printer down here, a Microline 192.
我看到了一个经典的针式打印机，型号Microline 192
One of their Personal Printers.
他们生产的个人打印机之一
And it was made to be a little bit smaller,
设计上就是小一些，不在桌面上占据过多位置
not take up as much space on a desk.
Not as impressive as some other dot matrices
没有其他的针式打印机那么好
but, it is what it is and I like seeing these.
不过，这是针式的啊，我挺喜欢的
Still had a ribbon in there too. Probably dry but, whatever.
貌似里面还有色带，八成干了
I'm not gonna hold that against it.
没啥可讨厌的
Okie-doke, Okidata.
Above that saw an Apple logo on a box that got my attention.
上面有苹果商标的盒子吸引了我
And it turns out to one of their AirPort Extremes.
看上去是一台 AirPort Extremes
One of the fifth generation ones from, I don't know,
貌似是第五代的，我不清楚
nine or 10 years ago or something.
大约十年前的玩意吧
Didn't check to see if it was in there but the box was darn heavy, so.
没拆包装，但是包装很沉
I just didn't care enough to check.
我不太感兴趣，就没拆
I cared a little bit more about this right here.
我略微对这个更感兴趣一点
We got a Sony Mavica.
这是一台Sony Mavica
Oh heck yeah-vica!
(不知道他在模仿谁)
I really enjoy these floppy disk cameras.
挺喜欢这种放软盘的相机
This is one of their FD-71 models.
这个的型号是FD-71
I'm not needing any more of them,
我不想再要一台了
but I always enjoy seeing them make an appearance.
不过能看见也挺高兴的
They're just fun little cameras.
挺耐人的小相机
And they provide an intriguing aesthetic to your photos.
拍出来的相片也有种有意思的感觉
And down below that, check this little thing out.
在这下面呢，看看这个13吋的CRT彩电，JVC牌子的
We've got a 13 inch CRT down here. JVC Master Command.
Yeah, really like the way this looked.
看上去挺顺眼的
$2. It's a color TV built in December of 1990
售价2美元，1990年12月生产的
and it's only got RF input. So I'm not gonna grab it.
而且只有RF输入，所以我不会买的
I just don't need any more RF little TVs of this size,
我不太需要这么大的RF彩电
but dang it. I liked the way it looks.
不过呢，真喜欢这外观
I hope somebody gives it a good home.
兴许其他人会有识货的吧
Huh! Well, this is a tad unusual for a Goodwill find,
哈，这玩意在Goodwill里可谓很难见到了
we get an EVGA PC ATX power supply down here. 500 watts for $20.
这是个EVGA PC ATX电源，功率500瓦，售价20美元
Just tossed in with the rest of the electrical crap over here.
他就和其他的电子零件放在一起
It's not modular or really anything special,
不是模块化的，没啥特别的
but worth pointing out, I suppose.
不过我觉得还是说一下吧
Alright. Yeah, we gotta check this out
好的，咱来看看这个
see that Slim Cam logo on the bag down there.
这个有Slim Cam标志的背包
What have we got here?
里面是啥呢？
We've got a Sharp Slim Cam.
这是一个夏普的Slim Cam录像机
It was indeed a slim camera.
这录像机确实很薄
A VHS one with Zoom 8 CAT'S EYE 2Lux artificial intelligence system. Yeah.
用的是VHS录像带，还有不知所云的人工智障系统:-P
I don't know man,
好高大上啊
but, that seemed pretty cool for what it is.
不过，看上去挺酷的
I just like the fact that it's slim considering it's full sized VHS in there.
考虑到里面是装的VHS录像带，这么薄的机身还挺耐人的
And then I also noticed this little guy, look at this.
再来看看这个耐人的小玩意
We got a Micronta alarm clock with a classy
这是Micronta牌的闹表，上面有点木纹:-)
little bit of woodgrain going on and you know,
this blue display, I just had to check it out.
还有这蓝色的显示屏，不得不驻足观看
It looked neat. So I plugged it in and what do you know?
看上去小巧玲珑，所以我接电测试一下了，结果
It's neat. I don't really need it but I just, again,
还挺好，虽然我不太需要，不过呢，看上去挺好的
I like looking at it.
So I looked at it and then I put it back.
我又爱抚了一会，放了回去
If I'm gonna buy an alarm clock, it's gotta be a little more special than that.
我要买个闹表的话，得比这个稍微更加特别些
Though that display here is pretty darn cool.
尽管这个的显示屏真是很酷啊
All right. Onto this Goodwill down this way and yeah,
好的，再去一家GoodWill，再看看旁边
they have finished the Panera Bread construction over there
那家面包店终于建完了
and it is finally open. I don't think inside.
而且还开门了，不过我没进去
I don't know. Maybe it is.
应该能堂食吧
The drive through definitely is.
不过汽车外卖绝对开张了
Anyway, Goodwill!
不管了，淘二手去！
That's why we're here.
要不我来这干嘛呢
And immediately up front
进店一上来
I see this box for a GE Deluxe Automatic Record Changer.
我看到了这台通用电气生产的的自动唱片切换机
But inside is not that.
然而里面不是这样
Instead we've got some components for another Magnavox turntable
相反，里面装的是一些 Magnavox 唱片机的组件
mid-century type of thing. Micromatic.
上世纪五十年代的玩意，牌子是Micromatic
注：Micromatic = Micro Mechanical
Gotta love model names like that.
牌子叫得很响
Advertisement: 迎面走来的是pdd代表队:-\
But yeah, that was all that was in here.
不过呢，里面就是这些东西了
Kind of underwhelming,
有点小失望
not even a complete thing.
甚至组件都不全:-(
Now this Case Logic cassette case on the other hand,
再来看看这个磁带盒子里面都有嘛
this is a little more of just more.
看上去东西有点多
Look at all these.
我的天哪
Got some Def Leppard, ZZ Top,
威豹的，ZZ Top的，Cheap Trick的
Cheap Trick, Bon Jovi, Neil Diamond, Beaches.
还有邦乔维的，Neil Diamond的，Beaches的
Someone's '80s tape collection ended up
八十年代流金岁月一下到手啊
最好的自由年代 由里根演讲
here all at once.
And then down in the case below that
而那个盒子的下面呢
looked like something that had never been opened or used,
貌似是个从来没有开箱使用过的东西
a Sima CopyKit 3.
是一个 Sima CopyKit 3
Home Theater Copy Center.
家庭影院复录一体机
I didn't take it out of the case,
我没有将其拿出盒子
but I was mighty intrigued by what I was seeing on the box itself.
不过我看到盒子的时候，还挺好奇的
Turns out this is kind of like a home telecine kit.
查了一下，这玩意相当于家庭胶卷录制机
Where you take a video camera, point it at this little lens area
你用个摄像机，将镜头对着放映机的投射镜头
and then whatever is projecting through the front of the copy kit
然后放映机放映出来的东西通过这个拷贝机
is transferred to your videotape.
就录制到录像带了
That's actually pretty cool.
实际上挺有意思的
I'd never seen one of these before and now I have.
我之前从未看过，现在我看到了
Let me know if you've ever used one of these.
你们要用过的话，去评论区留言吧
I'm curious how well it works.
我对这个东西的原理挺感兴趣的
And I gotta say, thrifting during a pandemic has been weird
我要插一句，疫情淘二手确实有点奇怪
but you're reminded of how weird it has been every so often with things like this.
不过有些事情确实能让你时常记起来这种情况，比如这个
Four rolls of toilet paper for a $1,
四卷厕纸一美元
SuperBart：我学校超市12卷是20多块，差不多是四个6.5元
也就是12卷19.5元，好像差不多了
which I mean there was a shortage.
疫情开始时，确实厕纸短缺
SuperBart: 当时电台天天报这个……这电台能多报人点好吗:-(
So, you know.
知道我的意思了吧
Same goes for hand sanitizer.
免洗洗手液也是这样
They had tons of these bottles, this store,
这家店有很多瓶的
and many of the other stores in the area.
其他店的类似区域也是这样
Alcohol antiseptic, 80% topical solution.
酒精浓度80%的外用消毒液
注：外用消毒用酒精溶液应该是75%!
Just kind of generic bottles
就放在这样的瓶子里
with a label slapped on there looking shady.
贴有十分可疑的标签纸
Hey, whatever. People needed this stuff
不管了，总有人需要的
and it was here at Goodwill.
而且Goodwill也有卖的
All right. Over in the furniture and look at this.
好的，来到家具区，我看到了这个
This is not a pool table,
这不是台球桌
even though that's what the tag said.
尽管标签上是这么标的
I mean, I guess it was technically kinda sorta correct.
好吧，我觉得在一定程度上，也挺对的
This is a Bumper Pool Table.
这算是个碰碰球台
It's a lot smaller than regular billiards.
比普通台球台可是小多了
But yeah. This might be the first one of these I've seen at Goodwill.
不过呢，我还是头一回在GoodWill里看到这个
So, that alone made it worth looking at for a second.
所以呢，就冲这一点，我也要看上几眼
And now we're not gonna look at it.
而这玩意，我要好好看看了
We're gonna look at this Wurlitzer over here,
这是个 Wurlitzer 电子琴
because man, look at this.
我们来仔细看看
The phenomenal retro-ness of it,
挺厉害的古旧设备啊
all those colorful keys, the key pad,
这么多彩色的按钮，还有小键盘
it's even got a built in compact cassette recorder.
甚至还有内置的磁带录制机呢
Augh!
:-)
Yeah, that's just awesome.
没错，这个很好的
It's no wonder somebody already bought it.
怪不得已经有人买了这个
Ah, this thing was neat.
这玩意真是太耐人了
I just approve.
就是这么耐人
It smelled like mildew and cigarettes.
闻上去有股霉味和烟味
Now these two boxes over here certainly got my attention
而这里的两个盒子吸引住我了
cause there were two of them.
因为这里有两个呢
And inside were a bunch of unused
而里面是一大堆没用过的6.5盎司高脚杯
six and a half ounce of wine glasses marked
California YR Convention 1980
上面标着 California YR Convention 1980
I think is what it said.
杯子上就是这么印的啊
I dunno why it cracks me up, but it does.
不知这玩意有啥可笑的，可我确实笑了
Yeah, there's two boxes of 'em.
没错，这里可有两箱呢
Anyway, take a look at this BASF!
无论如何，我们来看看这个BASF
Or rather enjoyably colorful floppy disc holder
也就是一个颜色鲜艳的软盘盒子
for five and a quarter inch diskettes.
可以用来装5.25英寸的软盘
B.A.S.F-branded goodness.
B.A.S.F 品牌的好玩意
I've got one pretty darn similar to this.
我有一个和这个十分相似的
No, I don't need it
还是别剁手了吧
but, you know what? floppy holders, they're fun.
不过软盘盒很有意思的
Even more fun with color.
尤其是颜色鲜艳的
Ooh. Hey, here we go.
好的，来看看这个
We got a CD player as old as I am 1986, Sony CDP-45.
看见个跟我一样大的CD机，1986年生产的索尼CDP-45
Much like myself the design is aged.
跟我一样，这设计很老旧了
Look at all the squares and the rectangles,
看看这个方块和三角形
the play and pause buttons.
也就是播放暂停按钮
I just like the way this looks always have.
我挺喜欢这个的外表，貌似一直都是这样
Up and over from there was another tape deck that I approve of.
而这上面的东西呢，是一个我很喜欢的卡座
This one being a Toshiba,
这个是东芝生产的
which is a brand I just don't see very often in terms of cassette decks.
在卡座方面，很少能看到这个牌子的
In fact, I can't think of any others I've ever seen thrifting.
实际上，自打我淘二手以来，基本没见过这个
I don't know.
兴许没注意吧
Regardless, It was a pretty sweet looking deck.
无论如何，这个卡座设计挺好看的
I like their design language.
这设计方式我喜欢
And the model number, PC-G50R.
这个的型号是 PC-G50R
Yeah. Good stuff.
确实是好玩意
Then I found this little thing down here.
然后我在那个卡座的下面找到了这个
Pretty intriguing as well.
也是个有意思的东西
This is a Radio Shack amplified video selector.
这个是 Radio Shack 牌的视频信号增强器
That's just a bunch of RF connectors on the back to go to different equipment.
该设备后面一堆RF接口，接到不同的设备
But, what intrigued me was all the remote control-like functions in a box.
但对我而言，更有意思的是上面的远程控制按钮
Like the fact that you could not only switch to a different
你不仅可以用这个切换监视设备
device to see, but also things like cable, auxiliary, VCR, antenna,
而且像线缆，辅助设备，录像机，天线啥的
that kind of thing in a box instead of the handheld remote.
也都能拿这个控制，这可解放了一堆遥控器了
And down below the clocks that were no doubt sold at Brendle's in 1990,
接下来的这个表，显然是于1990年在Brendle店里售卖
we had something that was a little more my style.
而再接下来的东西，挺合我的口味的
Check this out.
Tada
A MusicStar Multimedia Music System.
这个 MusicStar 多媒体音乐一体机
"Plugs into any PC with a sound card."
“插进任何有声卡的电脑”
Yeah!
:-D
Just a little mini keyboard for the PC.
给电脑设计的小电子琴
Or really anything.
或是差不多的玩意
The only thing that made this quote unquote "for the PC"
而这里提到的“为电脑设计”，是说
was the fact that it has an interface to plug into your sound card,
它有一个接口，可以插进你电脑里声卡的
the game port, as well as some software.
游戏接口，当然还要装一些软件
I have another one by Reveal that I plan to cover at some point.
我有一台相似的设备，Reveal生产的，计划出视频
So, I didn't grab this but,
所以，这个我没买
it was exciting to see a thrift store shelf like this.
但能在商店里看到这个，也是挺高兴的
And I also absolutely love this picture on the back.
还有后面的这图片，我太喜欢了
That Packard Bell setup, looks so much like my computer I had back then.
就那台 Packard Bell，挺像那时我有的那台
SuperBart: 我第一台电脑是在我五年级时候买的，里面有一个老版的 GT 630 :-P
Yeah. Let's see.
我们继续寻找
Down below that we got a box of eight track tapes,
下面有一堆八轨磁带
just loosely thrown in there.
就这么随便地扔在这里
A format that I'd still kind of like to mess around with at some point.
现在我仍然在某些时候使用这个东西
Especially with the recorders.
尤其是录音的时候
In fact, you'll see a blank one that has been recorded onto in here.
实际上，这里有个出厂空白的磁带，已经录上东西了
But yeah I just, you know, nothing I was needing in here or wanting, rather.
不过呢，这里没有我需要的，也没我想要的
Whatever, 8 track, it's a thing.
不过八轨磁带这事还是值得说一下的
Always has my attention.
永远能够吸引我
And checking out the CDs, because of course you gotta do it.
再看看这堆CD，我的老注意对象了
This stood out immediately,
而这个十分醒目
this little Palm desktop software package.
装有 Palm 系统电脑端软件的纸袋
I looked around the store to make sure that the PDA itself wasn't around somewhere.
我找遍商店，看看配套的PDA有没有在店里
That would be fun to get, but nope.
找的过程很愉快，可惜并没有:-(
Just the software, nothing special.
只有软件，没啥特别的
Apparently it was to a IIIxe Handheld, year 2000.
很明显这是 IIIxe Handheld 的配套软件, 发行于2000年
Mmhm.
行吧
All right. More electronics.
这里还有更多的电器
There's always more electronics.
真就一堆电器呗
What the heck is this?
这玩意是个嘛
A black and white and color line amplifier?
是叫黑白/彩色信号线路放大器吧？
You know, I don't know exactly what this does.
当然，我也不太知道这个东西的用途
Now I'm assuming it amplifies lines
我猜这个是放大线路上的信号
and a color and black and white variety with stuff going on.
并处理彩色信息，还是黑白信息啥的
Around back it had what appeared to be RJ-11 and S-video.
后面是RJ-11接口和S视频端口
Not the connections I was expecting to be honest.
说真的，后面的接口不是我想的那样
Anyway, the model number is HLA819MD. If you're interested in looking it up.
如果你想要一个的话，这个的型号是 HLA819MD
Ooh! And check this out.
再来看看这个
Up above that.
就在那个东西的上面
This kind of reminded me of that Technics M1
这让我想到了那台 Technics M1
注：Technics M1 是一个小型手提磁带播放机
that Techmoan covered at one point.
Techmoan 做过一期视频的
It's not that though.
当然这个并不是
This is a Sony Tran Sound CFS-3000 cassette recorder,
这是索尼的 Tran Sound CFS-3000 磁带录音机
or at least part of it.
至少是其中的一部分
The speakers aren't here.
这上面没有扬声器
So it's just this detachable little system in the middle
这应该是中间的可拆卸部分吧
but, I kinda really like the way that it looks without the speakers.
不过，这玩意没有扬声器也挺顺眼的
Who needs speakers?
自己家喇叭不香吗
You just plug in headphones, carry this around.
将耳机插进这里，然后四处乱逛
SuperBart: 某个长发青年(Homer)，带着墨镜，穿着喇叭裤，准备放Stay Alive……
That's my idea of a good time.
好时光就应如此
SuperBart: 然后打开磁带，“北~京，外国语大学……”
Oh! What is this?
天哪，这是个啥啊
Look at all this, big old beefy,
这个又大又沉的木头家伙
Panasonic wooden thing.
松下生产的
Has a solid wood cabinet, ah.
外壳很结实啊
And inside, got a solid state radio turntable.
里面呢，是有收音机的唱机，品相很好
Really cool kind of unit.
这玩意挺酷的
I don't see too many of.
我没见过多少
And down from there was another Panasonic thing,
而这下面的呢，也是松下生产的
a little bit newer.
不过稍微新一些
Also a turntable with a radio,
也是个有收音机的唱机
but had this intriguing dial area.
这个频率现实部分有点意思
It looks like it would be something if it lit up,
看样子调下台会发生有意思的事情
but, it's not lit up.
可惜并没有:-(
So, it's not much to look at here
好吧，这玩意没啥意思了
but, anyway, here's the thing.
不过值得一说
I like things.
还挺喜欢的
All right! One more Goodwill.
好的，再去一家GoodWill
Because, it's here. And I am too.
因为呢，他在这里，我也来了
And inside, hey, look at this.
然后里面呢，看看这个
They're selling toilet paper as well,
他们也卖卷纸:-P
but at least theirs is wrapped up
至少这是包装好的
and not just like random rolls tossed on a table.
而不是一卷一卷随意放在桌子上的
Over on the other side of the counter,
而在这家店的另一个角落里
I immediately noticed the little stack of PC games here.
我立马注意到这里有一摞电脑游戏
Really the standout one was "Zoo Tycoon 2 Endangered Species,"
显然，这里有个出名的 "动物园大亨二～濒危动物"
SuperBart: 不是宝石迷阵三吗？
but still, even in the smaller boxes, physical PC games at Goodwill,
不管咋说，GoodWill永远会有实体电脑游戏，就算包装盒很小
it's an increasingly not as common sight, which is just weird.
不过这倒是和平常不一样，有点奇怪
Let's take a second to admire this whole retro office set up
现在咱花些时间，致敬桌子上这堆古旧办公设备吧
kind of thing on this desk here.
We got the Rolodex,
这是个名片整理盒
we got the wedge, a little solar powered calculator and a pen holder
这是个Wedge，也就是一个太阳能计算机和一个小笔座
and a thing for like paper clips and whatnot, just stuck in a block of wood.
还有一个曲别针啥的东西卡在了这木头里面:-P
And then next to the leathery briefcase thing over here is this typewriter.
旁边这个大皮革箱子里面，是个打字机
"The Graduate", is what it's called.
牌子叫“毕业生”
Mrs. Sears, you're trying to seduce me.
Sears老师啊，你不能再引诱我用这个打字了
注：Sears是这个打字机的生产厂家
It almost worked.
这玩意基本上能用
All right. What is this?
好吧，这是个什么？
BBC Music...
BBC 音乐
Like that BBC?
是英国广播公司吗？
Yeah, I doubt it.
好吧，我有所怀疑
It's probably just from some church,
八成是从哪个教堂运来的
probably like Bible Baptist Church.
比如Bible Baptist Church（圣经浸礼宗教堂）
There's like a billion of those and they're all titled BBC around here, anyway.
这玩意有的是，都是标上了BBC的
I was just drawn to the spray paint stencil.
我只是被这喷漆字体吸引了过来
Nice touch.
挺好的
Also drawn to these little Franklin computers. Like always.
一如既往，我被这个 Franklin 小计算机吸引住了
Even though I have a couple of them,
尽管我已经有两台了
they're completely underwhelming.
而且很平淡无奇
Doesn't matter.
不过没啥关系
Little computery, retro things in your hand with an LCD,
能手握的小计算机，还有个LCD呢
this is the Word Master.
这个是 Word Master
It's just a dictionary. With a few other little features.
就是个词典，以及一些其他特性
It is what it is.
就这样
And then behind that, just gotta give props to the Fellowes floppy disk holder
而这后面的呢，挺喜欢这个Fellows牌软盘盒
as a fellow that holds a lot of floppy disks himself, I approve.
作为我们的好友(Fellow本意)，它能放很多的软盘，挺好的
Across from there, in the random junk section
我们现在来到了杂货区了
was bunch of random junk, randomly.
真就是各种杂货呗
And this junk randomly stood out.
而这个在这其中就很随意地显现了
It was a ceramic apple server pack
这是个陶瓷苹果餐具套装
still sealed for who knows how long.
谁知有多长时间没开封了
The thing that really kind of caught me off guard
这里面还有苹果饮料，挺让我惊讶的
was the fact that there were still cider mix in there.
That was just, who knows how old.
谁知道这玩意有多老了
It just amuses me to see these kinds of gifts that get re-gifted forever,
这玩意一直被人们赠送来，赠送去，怪搞笑的
or just end up in a closet for decades until it ends up at Goodwill.
或是在哪家的壁橱上放了十几年，最后出现在了GoodWill
Oh, check out these appliance boxes.
再来看看这些电器
That Emerson microwave on top,
上面是爱迪生牌微波炉
I admire how simple it is.
这设计真简洁
Literally a switch between cook and defrost and you got a timer, that's it.
只有解冻和烹制选项，再来一个定时器，就够了
And then down below that, that was another microwave
而这下面的呢，又是一个微波炉
with some awesome rainbows going on, but nope,
上面有些彩虹般的彩色条纹，我还是爱不起来
this is something called a Harvest Maid.
这东西应该叫做 Harvest Maid
Really it's just a dehydrator with a timer.
就一有定时功能的脱水机
Fantastic graphics.
这图标啥的挺好看
I don't know.
(本翻译无法继续处理意义不明的I don't Know)
It's old enough that it's weirdly appealing and kinda not.
这玩意足够老旧，好像有种奇怪的吸引力
And then finally, just browsing through some final electronics.
最终，当我在浏览电子区最后部分的时候
Noticed this Gateway 2000 desktop keyboard.
我注意到了 Gateway 2000 桌面键盘
Gateway 2000 solo: More Computing, More Spaces.
Not really old enough for anything I would want,
还没老到我想要的地步
but hey, at least it's beige.
不过，至少这个是米色的呢
Honestly though, It's what was above that,
不过呢，上面的东西才是我来看看这个货架的主要目的
that brought me over to this wall in the first place.
Check it out.
看看这个
Didn't know what I was looking at at first,
一开始我还没看出来这是个什么东西
but yeah, it's a little alarm clock lamp by Spartus.
后来明白过来，这是个带有闹表的台灯，Spartus生产的
And there's something about it that just
不知为何，我觉得他在叫我将他带回家
immediately was like screaming out to me to bring it home.
First I had to see if it worked.
首先上电，看看能不能用
I like the red LEDs in the wood grain,
我喜欢这个红色的LED，以及木纹
but if it doesn't work...
但要是没法用的话……
But no. Turns out it does work.
测试了一下，能用
The bulb works,
灯泡能用
the clock display works, everything works.
时间显示也有，一切正常
It's a little worn down after however many decades, but aren't, we all?
仅仅是经过了几十年后，有点陈旧了，不过我们不都是这样吗:-(
I'm taking it home.
我要把它带回家
And that is it for this episode of "LGR Thrifts."
本期“LGR淘二手就是这样啦”
You know, I only got two things over the last, what, eight months? 10,
好吧，我最终就买了这两个东西，经过了……等会，八个月吗？
I don't know how long it's been.
谁知道经历了多久了
It's been awhile, but that's fine.
确实很久了，不过还好
It's been a daggum journey getting here.
录制那么多素材可真是消时颇长啊
And I don't just mean going to thrift stores.
而且还不止去淘二手
I mean, not going to thrift stores.
也就是说，出门(大多)不是因为要淘二手
You know, just like everything else going on in the world.
就跟这个世界发生的其他事情一样
And whatever. I got a cool looking little lamp clock.
不管啥了，我搞到了这个外表很酷的闹表台灯
I love this thing.
真是耐死我了
I've been using it all the time.
买回来后，我一直在用呢
It's oddly enjoyable to just turn on and use
仅仅打开这个，然后在我处理小件
and bring into areas that I'm working on smaller electronics, man!
电器的时候带过去用，就有种奇怪的享受感
Does it have a smell!
还有这个味道啊
There's something about the way that it heats up
开灯的时候，里面白炽灯泡热了起来
with that little incandescent bulb in there
and the metal and the dust and everything else.
然后传到了金属，尘土啥的
It gets warm.
逐渐温暖了起来
And it has a...
他还有那种……
I don't know, it roasts in a certain old way. That's extremely nostalgic.
怎么说呢，某种特殊的糊味，超级怀旧的
Reminds me of a million things from childhood that just burned.
各种童年回忆啊，昨天忘掉的今天又都想起来了
Aight, whatever man. "LGR Thrifts," It's been a thing.
好吧，这就是"LGR 淘二手"了
And here's a bunch of your things that y'all have sent in,
接下来就是你们发给我的东西啦
in terms of your own thrifting finds over the past amount of time.
都是你们在过去几个月中买到的各种二手
Thank you as always for supporting the show
感谢大家一如既往对该系列的支持
and just showing general interest
跟我分享你们对这个的兴趣
and constantly asking like when a new "Thrifts" episode is going to come out.
还不停问我啥时候出品最新一期的“淘二手”
I wish I could do more.
我也想做的更多啊
I'm gonna try to do more.
我将会做得更多
You know, as things start to clear up and get somewhat more normal-esque.
毕竟，看样子形势已经好转，有点回到正轨了
Knock on woodgrain.
（再看看木纹)
We'll see. Right?
看着像是，对吧
But for now, this has been an episode.
不过呢，本期视频就这样吧
SuperBart: VS Code YYDS!
I hope that you enjoyed it and as always,
希望大家看得愉快，一如既往
thank you very much for watching!
非常感谢大家收看:-)
翻译：SuperBart 原作者LGR发布于2021-3-26
赞助原作者: https://www.patreon.com/LazyGameReviews
给LGR提供字幕: https://github.com/BenderBolg/LGR_Chinese_Subtitle
我的字幕下载： https://github.com/BenderBolg/Subtitles
有人能送给我一些有意思的小东西吗:-\